<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div>
  <div> 6 of 6 people found the following review helpful
  </div>
  <div>
    5.0 out of 5 starsMore a Java Programming Class than a Reference Book,
    <nobr>October 3, 2010</nobr>
  </div>
  <div>
    <div>
      <div>By </div>
      <div>
        Trent P. McDonald - See all my reviews
        <br/>
        (REAL NAME)   
      </div>
    </div>
    <div/>
  </div>
  <div>Amazon Verified Purchase(What's this?)</div>
  <div>This review is from: Head First Java (Paperback)</div>
  When you first glance through this book you will notice all of the retro
  pictures and half jokes. I've never read a Dummys/Idiots book on programming,
  but I can imagine them having the same look and feel. But then when you dig
  into the actual content...
  <br/>
  <br/>
  This book, to me, felt like a good class on Java programming from a great
  professor who has real world experience - the tone is conversational and the
  topics selected that make the most real world sense. There are a few large
  "class projects" that have a very real world feel to them (a networked beatbox
  anyone?). Important points are pounded home. It is the class but without the
  text book...
  <br/>
  <br/>
  The topics covered also seemed to have a "real person" feel as opposed to a
  textbook feel. I read another popular Java book just before this one. It threw
  2 chapters on GUI basics as almost an afterthought, there was no networking,
  nothing about inner classes, nothing about making distribution packages, etc.
  In that book the basic ideas were gone over in great depth, greater than here,
  but these more practical topics were skipped or had the briefest mentioned.
  <br/>
  <br/>
  With this book you start using Swing just a little more than half way through
  the book. All the topics in the last paragraph (plus many others) were covered
  in a practical method.
  <br/>
  <br/>
  This book, however, isn't perfect. As mentioned above, this book is like a
  good class on Java programming without the textbook. Sometimes the textbook is
  needed. When I was in school I always read the textbook no matter how good the
  prof - it was needed to get the full benefit of the info. I also like having
  good reference books that I can leaf through when I have an issue. This book
  is a mediocre, at best, reference book and admits it.
  <br/>
  <br/>
  It also often gets too cute. OK, sometimes that is needed, but it can get a
  little... As another reviewer mentioned, this books often seems to be aimed at
  collage age kids, not professional programmers. Not necessarily a bad thing -
  I've been out of my 20s longer than I care to admit and I never felt I was too
  old to be reading it.
  <br/>
  <br/>
  I would recommend this book if you are just starting off in Java or are rusty
  and want to pick it back up. I would also recommend getting a more
  conventional book as foil and as a reference.
  <div>
    <div>
      <div>Help other customers find the most helpful reviews </div>
      <div>
        <nobr>Was this review helpful to you? YesNo</nobr>
      </div>
    </div>
    <div>
      <div>
        <div>
          <nobr>Report abuse</nobr>
          |Permalink
        </div>
        <div>Comment Comment</div>
      </div>
    </div>
    <div/>
  </div>
  <br/>
</div>
