<article>
	<h1>
		Lucene Solr Expert Consulting Services and Tech Support
	</h1>
	<p>
		Tokenizer Inc. provides expert consulting for Lucene, Solr, and
		related technology frameworks such as LingPipe, GATE, WEKA, Mahout,
		Cassandra, HBase, Hadoop, MapReduce, focused on architecture and
		design reviews, performance optimization and best practices. The
		Tokenizer Inc. consulting team consists of senior technologists
		intimately familiar with Lucene/Solr and many other technologies,
		with
		extensive experience in field-tested search solutions in
		diverse
		deployment scenarios.
	</p>
	<p>
		By leveraging Tokenizer's deep domain expertise, you can achieve
		rapid transfer of knowledge on Lucene and Solr technologies, faster
		application development cycles, and assurance of utilizing well
		tested
		architectural design principles. Our customers also gain
		economic
		efficiencies by avoiding lengthy ramp-up times and costly
		design errors
		due to inexperience.
	</p>
	<p>
		The majority of consulting activities are conducted remotely to
		maintain cost-effectiveness.
	</p>
	<h2>
		Early Stage Evaluation
	</h2>
	<p>
		Key to the success of any search application is ensuring that the
		architectural design and configuration are grounded in best
		practices
		and align with the business and functional requirements.
		Tokenizer Inc.
		Enterprise Solution Architects can provide advice
		and recommendations
		for rapid and optimal development as well as
		deployment that ensure
		that:
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Your search application design meets business objectives
		</li>
		<li>
			Your search application effectively meets functional/technical
			requirements
		</li>
		<li>
			Best practices for indexing, searching and performance are
			utilized
		</li>
	</ul>
	<h2>
		Diagnostic Services
	</h2>
	<p>
		Tokenizer Inc. consulting services can cost effectively and
		rapidly
		analyze, troubleshoot and recommend fixes for complex
		search issues
		that arise from changes to your application or the
		content you are
		searching. Specific areas that benefit from such
		diagnostic assessment
		can include:
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Indexing
		</li>
		<li>
			Query
		</li>
		<li>
			Advanced search functions such as spellchecking, faceting,
			"more-like-this", autosuggest/as-you-type
		</li>
		<li>
			Configuration
		</li>
		<li>
			Performance analysis
		</li>
		<li>
			Scalability and capacity planning
		</li>
	</ul>
	<h2>
		Periodic Assessment
	</h2>
	<p>
		Tokenizer search experts can perform a periodic assessment of
		your
		Lucene/Solr based application, to help you ensure know that
		your
		application is performing optimally to meet your business
		objectives.
		To deliver optimum performance for search
		effectiveness, your dedicated
		Lucene/Solr Expert Consultant will:
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Analyze and optimize Query response times
		</li>
		<li>
			Verify accuracy and performance of data analysis and
			transformation
		</li>
		<li>
			Validate the search index integrity
		</li>
	</ul>
	<h2>
		Typical Tokenizer Inc. Consulting Engagement
	</h2>
	<p>
		Once you have completed a technical briefing with our engagement
		team, we will work with you to formulate a recommended approach to
		identifying your needs and requirements, and translating them into
		key
		focus areas. A typical engagement runs 5-7 days, not all
		consecutive,
		performed remotely to reduce your costs and accelerate
		the time you
		need to implement recommended improvements. Within
		these engagements,
		you can expect our experts to cover one or more
		of the following:
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Diagnostic/Assessment session
		</li>
		<li>
			Requirements analysis
		</li>
		<li>
			Architecture/Design review
		</li>
		<li>
			Benchmarking and baselining system attributes
		</li>
		<li>
			Best practices recommendations
		</li>
		<li>
			Tuning and performance optimizations
		</li>
	</ul>
	<p>
		At the conclusion of the engagement, Tokenizer Inc. delivers a
		thorough architectural design report with recommendations tailored
		to
		your specific needs and environment. Implementation of the
		recommendations and optimizations is performed by your software
		development staff; if need be, we can recommend a certified
		Tokenizer
		Inc. development partner to assist with implementation
		work as your
		require. Note that Tokenizer Inc. does not offer
		consulting on an
		ad-hoc hourly basis.
	</p>
	<p>
		Many customers discover that the set of recommendations and
		assessments produced for their initial consulting agreement are
		only
		the first step in an ongoing effort to keep their search
		environment
		current with their marketplace and technology needs.
		For those who
		understand that effective search requires continuous
		tuning and
		evaluation, Tokenizer Inc. offers ExpertLink, an annual
		subscription
		which includes a package of consulting hours that
		serves as a
		continuation of your initial project engagement.
		ExpertLink also
		includes a support packages, available at various
		service levels, to
		assist you with responding to specific issues
		that emerge during
		development, deployment and in production.
	</p>

	<h2>
		Get Started
	</h2>
	<p>
		To determine which consulting package is best suited for your
		situation, please
		<a href="http://www.tokenizer.ca/about-us/contact-us">contact Tokenizer Inc.</a>
		to arrange an initial requirements assessment. Once the discovery
		session is completed, Tokenizer Inc. will propose the consulting
		package for services and on-going support that best meet your needs
		and requirements.
	</p>
	<em>
		<a href="http://lucene.apache.org/">Apache Lucene</a>
		and
		<a href=http://lucene.apache.org/solr ">Apache Solr</a>
		are trademarks of Apache Software Foundation.
	</em>

</article>
