<article>
	<h1>
		Apache Cassandra Technical Support and Consulting Services
	</h1>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Our staff includes early Cassandra community members with
			experience in
			large production deployments on-premise and in EC2.
		</li>
		<li>
			We
			support clients on the Datastax
			enterprise
			offering as well as the
			Apache community offering.
		</li>
		<li>
			Our first priority is to review your needs and help you choose the
			most
			applicable technology solution
		</li>
		<li>
			We assist in a proof of concept, prototyping a system and
			supporting
			your development teams
		</li>
		<li>
			We ensure you have backups, monitoring, and configuration
			management
			set up.
		</li>
		<li>
			We benchmark, tune and optimize your Cassandra cluster to help you
			make
			the most out of it.
		</li>
		<li>
			We integrate ongoing support of the system with other systems we
			manage, providing world class operations support to keep you up and
			running and meeting your business goals
		</li>
		<li>
			We provide technical, architectural and product delivery
			leadership and
			mentoring to four Agile development teams
		</li>
		<li>
			We support product management/technology leadership in defining,
			sizing
			and prototyping new products by solving specific, challenging
			technical issues and related business problems
		</li>
		<li>
			We are exceptionally comfortable working in all tiers of a typical
			web
			application
		</li>
		<li>
			We have deep understanding and experience with traditional RDBMS,
			Column-Oriented DBMS, OO, SOA and REST
		</li>
		<li>
			Our team members have exceptional Python and Java development
			skills
		</li>
		<li>
			Apache Cassandra installation and configuration.
		</li>
		<li>
			Apache Cassandra schema design, data modeling, indexing, and query
			optimizations
		</li>
		<li>
			Apache Cassandra performance tuning
		</li>
		<li>
			Apache Cassandra clustering, replication, datacenter distribution,
			high
			availability, and scale
		</li>
		<li>
			Amazon EC2, iWeb, 1and1, Rackspace, and other deployments,
			including client
			premises
		</li>
		<li>
			Backup and recovery solutions
		</li>
		<li>
			<a href="https://github.com/Netflix/Priam">Priam</a>
			Support
		</li>
		<li>
			Client frameworks support, including Astyanax, Hector, Pycassa and
			more...
		</li>
		<li>
			Upgrades, maintenance, migrations and more...
		</li>
		<li>
			Access to an entire team of senior professionals with decades of
			production
			experience in their fields.
		</li>
		<li>
			24x7 support with a 30 minute SLA
		</li>
		<li>
			Transparency, teamwork and superior customer service.
		</li>
	</ul>
</article>